A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, National Affairs, Resources and the Environment, Office Files of William C. Pendleton FA658
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, National Affairs, Resources and the Environment, Office Files of William C. Pendleton
1965-1967
Rockefeller Archive Center
Pendleton, William C.
Ford Foundation
FA658
0.38 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged in 2 series by file type.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Subject Files, 1965-1967
Series II. Meetings and Trips, 1965-1966
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Subject files, meeting and trip records.
Biographical / Historical
William Clyde Pendleton (1923-2011) worked at the Ford Foundation for over ten years. He joined the Foundation as a Program Associate in the Economic Development and Administration Program. Following a change in the Foundation's program structure, he became a Program Officer in the Division of National Affairs, Urban and Metropolitan Development Program in 1966. He served in that position until 1974 when he moved to the Office of Resources and the Environment where he worked as a Program Officer. After another change in the Foundation's program structure, Pendleton spent his last years at the Foundation as a Program Officer in the Division of National Affairs.
Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, Pendleton taught at the University of Florida and the University of Pittsburgh. He served in the U.S. Navy during World War II.
Pendleton earned a B.A. in history from Brown University and a Ph.D. in economics from the University of Chicago.
- Subject Files, 1965-1967; I
  - Economic Development Administration (EDA) Program Memoranda, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Other Program Memoranda, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
- Meetings and Trips, 1965-1966; II
  - Meetings and Trips (Box 1)
  - South Bend Quota Conference, 1965 June 24-25 (Box 1)
  - International Economic Association -- Rome, Italy, 1965 September 1-8 (Box 1)
  - IEA East-West Meeting, Bellagio, Italy [PHOTOS], 1965 September 5-11 (Box 1)
  - Trip -- California, 1965 October 3-8 (Box 1)
  - New York City Transit Strike, 1966 February 24 (Box 1)
  - Sacramento -- Charles Hitch, 1966 May 24 (Box 1)
  - EDA Summer Institute -- Williams College, MA, 1966 June-July (Box 1)
  - Trip -- Alaska, 1966 July (Box 1)
  - Conference on Government Expenditures, Brookings Institute, Washington DC, 1966 August 14-16 (Box 1)
  - Trip -- Europe (IEA-CNRS, Regional Science Association), 1966 August 21-September 11 (Box 1)
  - Residential Needs in Highway Transportation -- Saratoga Springs, NY, 1966 October 25-26 (Box 1)
  - Southern Economic Association, Atlanta GA, 1966 November 11 (Box 1)
  - NASBO, 1966 November 19 (Box 1)